# Surendra Vikram Singh

User Interface Developer

% http://svsdesigns.in

*■* svsdesigns85@gmail.com

**\** 7774008187

#### **ABOUT**

A self taught UI Developer based in India with 6 yrs of experience in developing high-performance, cross-browser compatible & responsive web applications using major front-end technologies. Recently worked on Facebook, Behance & 500px API and integrated them with AngularJS. Has been an integral part of major projects like Alcatel-lucent, SABMiller, Sainsbury & NATS. Designs featured in Smashing Magazine, ELLE & The Hindu.

### **SKILLS**

**HTML & CSS** 

Proficient

**Javascript** 

Intermediate

**Adobe Photoshop** 

Intermediate

**Adobe Illustrator** 

Intermediate

## **EDUCATION**

Diploma In Web Designing

TGC, New Delhi- 2008-2009

**B.E In Electrical & Electronics** 

CSIT. Bhilai- 2003-2007

### ON THE WEB

https://dribbble.com/svsdesigns

Bē https://www.behance.net/svsdesigns

http://stackoverflow.com/users/1160568/svs

in http://in.linkedin.com/in/svsdesigns

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Synechron** / Sr. Associate - Software April 2013 - September 2014

Developed complex, cross-browser compatible, responsive websites using SASS, Grunt and custom Boilerplate for code maintenance and seamless workflow. Worked on projects like Alcatel-lucent, SABMiller, Sainsbury, NATS, UAE PMO, Strutt and Parker, MSL Group UK & 24/7 Media.

## Fabulloso / UI Designer/Developer

December 2011 - April 2013

Designed, developed and implemented themes for Magento & Wordpress. Keeping user-centric designs in mind developed interactive features & easy to use interfaces using latest web technologies and various UX techniques. Optimized the code for better performance and cross-browser compatibilities. Websites showcased by ELLE & The Hindu.

#### **Knowlarity Communication** / UI Designer

September 2010 - December 2011

Responsible for front-end design & development of complex web based applications in coordination with developers.

Developed templates using latest technologies (HTML5, CSS3 & Jquery). Designed Android User interface for one of the major Government projects.

## Digisoft Pvt. Ltd. / Web Designer

January 2009 - August 2010

Worked independently for designing and developing static websites. Designed & developed websites for Jaypee Cement, Flex Foods & many more reputed companies. Also worked on Joomla template customization & Search Engine Optimization.